Preliminary Guide to the Collection of Student Printing
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of student printing
1936-1987
AOB 80
Yale University Arts Library
1.67
(4 boxes)
This collection contains printed matter produced by students at various University Presses.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Collection of Student Printing was housed in the former Arts of the Book Collection until its transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains printed matter produced by students at various University Presses.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Wesleyan University Press, 1941-1974. II. Oxford Press, 1959-1973. III. Rhode Island School of Design Press, 1987. IV. Other University Presses, 1936-1980.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Press; Oxford University Press; Rhode Island School of Design
- Wesleyan University Press, 1941-1974; Series I
  - Nugae, 1941 (Box 1, Folder I.1)
  - To My Homeland, 1943 (Box 1, Folder I.2)
  - Brownstone, 1944 (Box 1, Folder I.3)
  - The Concept of Cubism, 1946 (Box 1, Folder I.4)
  - The Celebrated Jumping Frog of Calaveras County, 1951 (Box 1, Folder I.5)
  - Printing Types, 1951 (Box 1, Folder I.6)
  - The New Adam, 1953 (Box 1, Folder I.7)
  - Dover Beach, 1956 (Box 1, Folder I.8)
  - Poems by Federico Garcia Lorca, 1956 (Box 1, Folder I.9)
  - Printmaker's Chronology, 1957 (Box 1, Folder I.10)
  - Printmakers Chronology, 1958 (Box 1, Folder I.11)
  - Three Seasons', 1958 (Box 1, Folder I.12)
  - A Bibliography for Printmakers, 1959 (Box 1, Folder I.13)
  - The Blind Prophet, 1959 (Box 1, Folder I.14)
  - Fifteenth Century Book Illustration, 1959 (Box 1, Folder I.15)
  - The Invention of Paper, 1959 (Box 1, Folder I.16)
  - Greensongs, 1960 (Box 2, Folder I.17)
  - The Raven, 1960 (Box 2, Folder I.18)
  - The Title Page, 1960 (Box 2, Folder I.19)
  - Walt Whitman Selected Poems, 1960 (Box 2, Folder I.20)
  - A Showing of Type and Ornament in the Art Laboratory, 1962 (Box 2, Folder I.21)
  - The McIntire Garden House on the Endicott Estate, 1962 (Box 2, Folder I.22)
  - Thru These Eyes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder I.23)
  - Winter's Folly, 1962 (Box 2, Folder I.24)
  - Ancient Customs Used in a Printing House, 1963 (Box 2, Folder I.25)
  - Giambattista Bodoni, 1963 (Box 2, Folder I.26)
  - The First Noel, 1964 (Box 2, Folder I.27)
  - Thomas Bewick, 1964 (Box 2, Folder I.28)
  - Two Wood Engravings by Thomas Bewick, 1964 (Box 2, Folder I.29)
  - Thomas Bewick (1753-1828), 1965 (Box 2, Folder I.30)
  - Wood Engraving, 1965 (Box 2, Folder I.31)
  - 5 Woodcutters, 1966 (Box 3, Folder I.32)
  - Creepy Creatures, 1966 (Box 3, Folder I.33)
  - Himalayan History, 1966 (Box 3, Folder I.34)
  - The Serene Severities of Typography, 1966 (Box 3, Folder I.35)
  - The Serene Severities of Typography, 1966 (Box 3, Folder I.36)
  - A Book About Curious Insects, 1967 (Box 3, Folder I.37)
  - The Quick Brown Fox, 1967 (Box 3, Folder I.38)
  - Collection, 1969 (Box 3, Folder I.39)
  - Did Bruno Wassertile Ever Make You Smile?, 1974 (Box 3, Folder I.40)
- Oxford Press, 1959-1973; Series II
  - The Manner of Sir Philip Sidneyes Death, 1959 (Box 3, Folder II.1)
  - Character or Essayes, 1958 (Box 3, Folder II.2)
  - A Draught of Sir Philip Sidney's Arcadia, 1960 (Box 3, Folder II.3)
  - A Light in Darkness, 1963 (Box 3, Folder II.4)
  - The Book in the Netherlands, 1965 (Box 3, Folder II.5)
  - The Castell of Helth, 1970 (Box 3, Folder II.6)
  - Specimen of Engraving on Wood, 1972 (Box 3, Folder II.7)
  - Specimen of Engraving on Wood, 1973 (Box 3, Folder II.8)
- Rhode Island School of Design Press, 1987; Series III
  - Mediocrity, 1987 (Box 4, Folder III.1)
  - Untitled, 1987 (Box 4, Folder III.2)
- Other University Presses, 1936-1980; Series IV
  - The Treasure in the Forest, 1936 (Box 4, Folder IV.1)
  - To the Nile, 1950 (Box 4, Folder IV.2)
  - Cuas 6, 1959 (Box 4, Folder IV.3)
  - Late Lines, 1974 (Box 4, Folder IV.4)
  - An Account of the Hunting, Dressing, and Cooking of the Squirrel and Rabbit, 1977 (Box 4, Folder IV.5)
  - Gesta Typographa, 1980 (Box 4, Folder IV.6)